

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Details

Christchurch New Zealand 022 541 4990 peter.hind47@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

GitHub

Skills

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

TypeScript

React

Node.js

Express.js

SQL

Solidity

Blockchain

Git

Teamwork

Leadership / Management

People

Languages

English

Japanese

Hobbies

I'm a skilled Aikido Instructor and Competitor, and have captained both University and National teams.

Profile

Hello! I'm Pete, and I build things on the internet.

After a decade of Sales, Marketing and Management I've finally transitioned into the tech space as a software engineer. I've had a passion for tech and code since I was a kid - I wrote my first program on a BBC Microcomputer at the age of six. It wasn't game-changing software believe it or not, but I enjoyed it all the same!

With plenty of client-facing and management experience, I'm all about bridging the gap between people and software.

Employment History

Full-Stack Web Developer, Dev Academy Aotearoa, Christchurch

AUGUST 2023 - DECEMBER 2023

An intensive four-month long course replicating a genuine software development environment.

- Over 900 hours experience in a modern tech-stack, incorporating Node.js,
 React, Express, SQLite3 and many others.
- Working with others on both quick-turnaround and longer-term projects using Agile Methodologies. My existing human and people skills were a real strength here, and enabled my teams to build some great applications.
- My largest project was an app for Parents to assign chores to their kids and reward them for their efforts! This was a lot of fun to build and a great challenge with a small team in a short space of time.

Key Achievement:

- Our <u>ChoreQuest app</u> was well received by all our peers and mentors, and I received very positive feedback from other industry professionals on the strength of my <u>presentation</u> skills when demonstrating its functionality to an audience.

$Sales \&\,Marketing\,Specialist, In Style\,Timber\,Products, Melbourne$

NOVEMBER 2018 - AUGUST 2023

A hybrid role focussed on client interactions and marketing. This consisted of B2B sales work, as well as producing marketing collateral for a variety of Timber Products.

- Maintenance and design work on company website, including unified branding, email campaigns and development work.
- Working as part of a tight-knit team of seven in a fast-paced environment.
- OHS Administrator role including first-aid, safety induction and risk assessment responsibilities.
- Fielding sales/technical calls and building rapport with a variety of architectural clients.

Key Achievement:

- Development of an App to streamline our receipting process for imported products. The App could take an invoice from an overseas company, convert imperial measurements to metric, calculate costs, and produce a CSV file for direct upload to our ERP. This saved our purchasing team an average of 10-15 hours per week.

Career Break, Travel, Japan, Nepal & SE Asia

SEPTEMBER 2015 - NOVEMBER 2018

My partner and I took the opportunity to use some savings and go on an extended OE before settling down. I was lucky enough to meet some amazing people and experience some fantastic ways of life during this period.

Sales Representative / Technical Support, Criterion Industries, Melbourne

NOVEMBER 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2015

A client-facing role involving the design of office partitioning suites for a variety of applications.

- Extended, technical and focussed discussions with architects and contractors regarding the design and installation of a variety of aluminium office suites.
- Contributing to the design and development process of new products and installation guidelines.
- Assisting non-technical staff members in their understanding of the products and best marketing practices

Key Achievement:

- Recognising several communication issues between sales and floor staff enabled me to implement a number of time-saving procedures in the manufacturing and packing process.

Internal Sales Manager, Bellbird Building Supplies, Melbourne

MARCH 2010 - NOVEMBER 2014

A fast-paced role for a popular building supplies company in SE Melbourne, overseeing a small sales team of 4 - 6 people.

- Managing and delegating sales work for a variety of high-profile clients, and liasing with our external team of Sales Representatives.
- Training, onboarding and mentorship of junior members of the growing sales team.
- Direct contact and rapport-building with a diverse range of clients, from local builders to major construction companies.

Key Achievement:

- Working my way up from Warehouse Manager, to Sales, to Sales Manager gave me a comprehensive understanding of how the company worked, enabling me to identify possible issues with more complex orders/situations where others couldn't.

Education

New Zealand Certificate in Applied Software Development (Level 6), Dev Academy Aotearoa, Christchurch

AUGUST 2023 - DECEMBER 2023

- Intensive four month course designed to replicate a developer environment
- Over 900 hours of experience in a modern tech-stack

BA - Bachelor of Arts in Japanese Studies, The University of Sheffield., Sheffield

SEPTEMBER 2004 - SEPTEMBER 2008

- Graduated with Class 2:1 Honours
- Captain of University Sport Aikido Team

BA - Study Abroad Program, Hiroshima University, Hiroshima

SEPTEMBER 2006 - SEPTEMBER 2007

- Immersive Japanese language study
- Active in University Aikido and Kendo Circles